Jalerson Lima, MSc

Senior Web Developer

Phone: +55 (84) 98722-8804 **Website:** http://jalerson.me

E-mail/Hangouts: jalerson@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/jalerson

Skype: jalerson

GitHub: http://www.github.com/jalerson

Summary

Senior Web Developer and Project Leader at the Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Healthcare. Professor of Software Development and Engineering at the Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte. Master in Systems and Computing at the Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte.

Experience and Skills

- 10+ years of software development experience using a variety of front and back-end technologies, platforms and tools (Java, PHP, Ruby, Rails, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript and Python);
- Experience on gathering and negotiating functional requirements with clients;
- Starting several software projects from scratch;
- Conducting solo software projects but also working collaboratively using Git, GitHub, GitLab and BitBucket:
- Experience using MySQL and PostgreSQL in several projects;
- Proficient English communication and presentation skills: weekly meetings in English with supervisors and collaborators during my master's degree research.

Work Experience

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Healthcare – Natal, Brazil

Senior Web Developer and Project Leader 2012 – Present

Currently, I'm the main web developer and leader of the Telepediatria project. Telepediatria is a web-based system, developed in Ruby on Rails, to support non-specialist doctors in pediatric appointments, allowing them to discuss cases with remote medical specialists. I started this project from scratch: negotiating and collecting functional requirements with medical specialists. Telepediatria got the attention of Brazilian pediatric specialists when it was presented on the Brazilian Conference of Pediatric Endocrinology and Metabolism, due to its valuable features to support non-specialist and specialist doctors in pediatric appointments, as well as giving support to cases discussion and medical research.

I also had the opportunity to start, from scratch, the Dengue National Observatory, which is a web-based system, built in Ruby on Rails, to support public healthcare agents to track cases and proliferation spots of the *Aedes Aegypt* mosquito. System in action: http://youtu.be/kWvhaHXv-70.

During two months, I also coordinated the SISCOAPES project, which is a web-based system built in Django, to support the federal government in monitoring the operation of medical residents in healthcare centers. All the system features were remotely negotiated with public healthcare specialists from the Brazilian Ministry of Health.

Sync Systems - Natal, Brazil

Senior Systems Analyst 2009 – 2010

Senior web developer of the internal management system of the Telepesquisa Company, built in Ruby on Rails. Project built by me from scratch: negotiating and collecting functional requirements at client's site. The Telepesquisa management system had to import millions of records of other partner companies. I also was the main developer of the Bluesync, which is a Bluetooth marketing software developed in Java.

Symetrix Corp. – Colorado Springs, USA

Remote Systems Analyst Consultant 2008 – 2009

Remote Systems Analyst Consultant of the Eye of the Eagle project, which was a system to prevent tax evasion of the Rio de Janeiro government. I worked in Java, C and C# components, handling with smart cards and RFID (Radio-frequency Identification). In this position, I had my first experience negotiating features and deadlines with the clients in English.

Real Security - Natal, Brazil

Developer and Software Architect 2007

I worked as a software developer and architect to develop an Electronic Security Monitoring System used by the company. The system, built in Java, had to manage all the security signals sent by devices located in the clients houses.

Ministry of Education – Brasília, Brazil

Web Developer 2007

I worked as web developer to build the Knowledge Connections Portal to the Secretary of Continuing Education, Literacy, Diversity and Inclusion of the Ministry of Education. The portal, developed in Mentawai (Brazilian MVC Java Framework), it was nationally used to register and monitor projects conducted by federal universities.

Brazilian Agency for the Aquaculture Development – Natal, Brazil

Web Developer 2006

Web developer of the RECARCINE Portal, built in PHP, which was a portal for the Brazilian Agency for the Aguaculture Development.

Education

Master of Science in Systems and Computing

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte – Natal, Brazil 2012 – 2014

Specialist in Systems Engineering

Open Superior School of Brazil – Vila Velha, Brazil 2008 – 2010

Bachelor of Science in Software Development

Federal Institute of Education 2004 – 2007